Hi
How was your day?
The pipes burst at
Manokhin's building site
''Mother, mother, what will we do.
Mother, mother, how will we live. ''
How's our A-student?
He's out with friends
Vovka!
I forgot to buy bread,
could you nip out...
and buy some noodles?
Comrade, that man says
he's an alien, we have
to do something
Call the police
I will, but he's barefoot,
he'll catch a cold
Hello!
Hello.
I smell bad, I'm sorry
It's cold. I got this
from that metal box
Well done
Friend!
Please tell me your
planet number in tentura,
or at least the galaxy
number in the spiral
I've got the contacts
mixed up and now
I can't get home
We don't know the
number mate, we forgot it
Look, let's send this lad
to the information office,
and we'll wait for him
together in the bakery, OK?
Here,
put this on
Thank you.
Listen, friends,
there's no need for
an information office...
or bakery
This is my planet,
Uzm, 247
in tentura,
galaxy Beta
in the spiral
This is my space-
transportion gadget
So, which button
do I press to get home?
Because time is relative,
you understand that, right?
OK, I have
a proposition
We will press a button...
and transport
to your place
But if the device
doesn't work...
you will transport with us
to where we tell you, deal?
You can't just press it,
you have to know!
Yes we can...
What do you see?
Sand
So the fucking gizmo worked
And that jerk with the holes,
was he left behind?
Calm down, calm down
We have sun,
sand and gravity
We are on Earth or...
Or?
No,
we'll assume we're on Earth,
in some desert
Say, Karakum
What other deserts
do we have?
Gobi, Sahara...
I said we have!
Kyzylkum
No. We'll assume
it's Karakum
So, sun is to the West,
Ashabad is there
Let's go
Come on!
Comrade,
what's your name?
Vladimir Nickolaevich
My name is Gedevan
Pleased to meet you
You have a bottle in your case
Is it wine?
No, vinegar
I also have some herbs
We're all set then
Vladimir Nickolaevich,
do you remember the
number he mentioned
the guy who has my sock?
No
Maybe we're on his planet?
Listen, Fiddler...
we can guess all we want
but it's bloody pointless
We've chosen a direction
and that's where we're heading
We just need to get to the water.
Clear?
Vladimir Nickolaevich,
I want to change into slippers
Well do it!
Well stop then!
What time is it?
Four
In the morning?
Yes
Are you late
somewhere?
It's embarrassing
I called from the
airport, said I'd be
there in an hour, and...
You study music?
It's not mine
We had a concert
in my hometown,
and they forgot to put
the violin on the plane
Banquet?
Just a dinner
Oh.
Are you from Tbilisi?
Batumi
I thought I'd return
the violin and still catch
the train to my college
I study textile
manufacturing
Aha
I wanted to study
Foreign Politics,
but they said...
Quiet!
A man
Hello
It's a capitalist country
Do you speak any
foreign languages?
English, a little French
Tell them we
have no money
Tell them!
They want to be paid!
Hello!
We are our tourists,
we lost our group
Please give us a ride
to the nearest city,
and we'll find our
way from there
Translate
Hello
Chatl!
We have no money
We left money, passports
and foreign currency
with our guide
We stepped aside
for a moment and got
lost in the sands
Here. It's warm
Pardon?
You want my hat?
Here you go
It's not mine,
I can't give it away
There's nothing in there
Open it
It's not wine,
it's vinegar
Sour, right?
So mate, will you
give us a lift?
Fiddler, hurry up
Just to the nearest city,
we'll be all right there
You want my jacket?
Glad I didn't give
them the violin
Looks like they're sorry
Ketse!
Ketse what?
I think he
wants a match
You want a match?
Here
The whole box?
Get us out of here,
and we will koo
Not a single letter,
not a single 'made in'
Sorry,
I don't understand.
What do they want?
They want koo
Tsak!
Thank you
He wants me
to put on a bell
He'll have
to do without
I'll put it on.
It's too awkward
Go ahead
Oh, all right
I'll just have a cigarette
Ketse!
Calm down, calm down!
Vladimir Nickolaevich,
maybe we're really on...
Yeah right, they're
typical Martians
Lucy dear, you silly bitch.
You just hadto have those
noodles didn't you?
So. You speak Russian
Why did you hide it?
We didn't
It's hard to penetrate
your language when your
thoughts are bilingual
And this Patsak always
thinks in languages
he hardly knows!
What are you looking at,
mimuna verishvilli?
They speak Georgian, too!
What did he say?
Ape son of a donkey
All right!
We are from the Soviet Union,
here on a cultural exchange
Everybody knows
where we are
If you don't put us in
touch with the embassy...
you'll be in big trouble,
got it?
We don't understand embassy
Put the tsak back!
You understand 'Noodles'
and you understand 'mimuna',
yet you don't know 'embassy'?
You poor things
Quit messing with us!
You thought about noodles,
I simply said it
It's not Earth,
and it's not Africa mate
It's planet Pluk, 215 in tentura,
in the galaxy Kin-Dza-Dza in the spiral
Got it?
Well hello, here we are
Put the bell on mate
Well done
Excuse me,
where are we?
Hush! He has
very sharp ears
Do you know the tentura
of your planet?
Tentura?
Well, tell us your
Galaxy number in the spiral
In the spiral?
Yes, in the spiral, in the spiral
Well, Earth is... next to
planets like Venus,
Saturn, Jupiter...
Vladimir Nickolaevich,
what else?
Ursa Major
Vladimir Nickolaevich,
come here
Do you have more matches
on your planet?
I can get some
How many will you give us
if we put you there?
How many do you want?
Two boxes like that!
Seven!
And give me this box now,
I'll buy a gravitsapa
Excuse me,
what is a gravitsapa?
Without it pepelats
can only fly like this...
but with it - to any place
in the universe in 5 seconds
Gentlemen, you don't even
take a pepelats out of the
garage without a gravitsapa?
We had a gravitsapa,
but when we came here,
it got pinched
Excuse me, do you have a
space-transporting gadget?
No
Give me the matches
Give us some water
Like this!
This is yours;
this is how you smoke now
Thank you
He said he has
a gravitsapa
Put your matches here
No.
When you put us on Earth,
you'll get this and this
What?
Let's go, Fiddler,
to Outer Space
Stop!
Give it!
Only on mother Earth
Vladimir Nickolaevich,
you said if we get you to the
city, you'd give us all of it!
And you already stole
one match from us!
Patsaks do not
cheat on Patsaks,
it's wrong, mate
I said - to the city!
And what is this?
A barn
And this?
How is it's not a city?
Stop messing around
Let's see that gravitsapa.
If it's a major brand
- we'll take it
Patsak!
No one will touch
smuggled ketse
in front of witnesses,
you can get etsih for life
with nails for it!
What do you have in your head,
brains or kyoo?
We'll buy it ourselves.
Let's go
Stop!
Who are you?
Alien,
construction site foreman
No,
you are Patsak
And who are you?
I'm Georgian
No,
you're also Patsak
You, you and him
are Patsaks
And I'm Chatlan,
and they are Chatlans,
so put on the tsak
and stay in the pepelats,
got it?
What?
Look at me through
the scanner, mate
See,
it's a green colour
Same for him and you
Now look at Uef,
orange colour
That's because
he is Chatlan.
All clear?
What?
Pluk is a Chatlan planet
So, we Patsaks,
have to wear tsaks
And in front of us Chatlans,
you have to do this!
Vladimir Nickolaevich,
this is overtly racist
Show us again please
Like this!
Slower, please
Like this
Look, you have a wife,
a son struggling
for a C average,
and you are behind
on your mortgage
You don't want to
mess with us, mate
OK, Fiddler,
we'll play their game
Well done.
Give a match to Uef,
he'll buy a gravitsapa
He said he needed
them all
I was joking
Gentlemen,
you are so funny!
Wait!
We'll go together
Don't show them
any of your ketse,
and don't think about them,
just show them mine
And don't give them
more than half a match
Your Patsak said
it costs a whole match
He was joking too
Concrete mark 300
Patsak! Remember,
half or less
OK
Excuse me,
are Chatlans and Patsaks
different races?
No
Biologically different?
People from
different planets?
No
So how are
they different?
Are you colour-blind, Fiddler?
Can't you tell green from orange?
Tourist!
Hey!
It's a skyscraper!
Go, go
Do as I taught you
Hi missy.
Aren't you cold
in this coat?
They won't let me in,
they want you alone
Don't give them the ketse,
bring the gravitsapa here,
I'll check it
Go!
No
We're together
Vladimir Nickolaevich,
tell him!
Wait here
Don't go anywhere
Hi!
What's up?
You want me
to squat?
Well, out of respect
for the ladies
So what's
new on Pluk?
Put ketse here and
you'll get a gravitsapa
A half
Half it is
Can I take a look?
Sure
I'm not an expert
We'll show it to my
Chatlan, he'll check it
Just a moment while
we install the tsapa
Sore throat?
It's water
I have a proposition
I'll give you the rest
of this ketse for
two bottles of water
Ok
Do you have food?
Cereals
What kind?
Plastic
I'll give you this whole ketse
for five bottles of water
and a kilo of cereals
What's this?
Ketse
We have to
check it again
Check
Hey,
just a moment!
Be right back
Fiddler, can you get
matches on Earth?
Yes
If you can spit
further than me,
I'll give you half a chatl
If I can spit further,
you'll give me
two matches
Understood?
No
It's a simple game.
I bet half a chatl,
you bet 3 matches. Spit
No, thank you
OK, you bet one match,
I bet three chatls,
yellow pants
and I'll give you
a head-start like this.
Come on!
No
Blue pants!
Mr Uef,
under no circumstances
will I do this
Is this your
final word?
Then why are you
messing with me,
mimuna verishvilli!
Mr Uef! I represent a
civilised planet and demand
you to watch your lexicon!
Yeah!
Where are they?
Who?
That one,
with a scar
I'm such a moron,
I gave him all the matches
Gentlemen,
that's enough
Enough?
I told him we should
go to the Centre
But he's greedy like
all Chatlans, he decided
to save 2 chatls!
I have another one
Enough to buy
a gravitsapa, right?
Give it to me
Why?
To buy a gravitsapa
Where?
There,
in the Centre
How will you get
us to Mother Earth
if you don't even know
which galaxy it's in?
You moron, we can get
your planet number
from any planetarium
in the Centre for 2 chatls!
Give me the match
So you can bury
us in the sand?
Will you give it to me?
No
Is this you final word?
Couldn't be more final
Farewell then, mate
Vladimir Nickolaevich,
they'll fly off
No way, they'd
rather die than
leave the match
Either you give us
the match now,
or we won't put
you on Earth for
less than 7 boxes!
Yes you can, mate
Mr. Bee,
I have 50 roubles
Matches cost
2 kopeks per box,
so I can buy 2500
Fiddler's fibbing!
He has more chatls
Mr Uef! Don't call me Fiddler,
my name is Gedevan Alexandrovich
Is the engine there?
Quit poking around,
Gedevan Alexandrovich
Gedevan, let's
tie them up and plot a
course to the North
What for?
Maybe the
Mediterranean Sea is there
Vladimir Nickolaevich,
are you nuts, mate?
Pluk has no seas
They have been made
into luts long ago
Excuse me,
into what?
Into fuel, Fiddler
You owe us
6140 boxes
Why so much?
You ate cereals,
you drink water,
plus the widget
Cross that out, we are
not buying the widget.
Put it back
We need to bring back
a sample of technology,
or no-one will beleive us
If you want the
widget so much,
give them the violin
It's an Italian
antique worth more
than 1000 roubles,
how would I ever
pay it back?
Fiddler, instead of thinking
that you are the first
Georgian astronaut
and that you'd
get a Nobel prize,
give back the
spoon you stole
from us poor artists
I wasn't thinking
any of that
I wanted to donate it to science,
maybe it's some new metal
There's never been a Patsak
as pathetic as you, Fiddler
I'm devastated
Where are you going?
To the toilet
You can't take
money to the toilet
Leave money here,
Gedevan Alexandrovich
Ketse is very
expensive, mate
Why?
Well how, on Earth
do you determine
how many times who
has to squat in
front of whom?
We just play it by the ear
Barbarians!
Look,
I like you,
so I'll teach you
If I have
some ketse,
I have a right to
wear yellow pants
Also Patsaks have to
squat in front of me
not once, but twice
If I have a
lot of ketse
I have the right to
wear purple pants
and Patsaks have to
squat in front of me twice!
and Chatlans
have to koo
and etselops can't
beat me up at night,
never!
I have a
proposition, mate
You give us
the match now
and later we will bring
you yellow pants, deal?
Thanks, I already have a pair,
maybe Fiddler needs some?
Hey Fiddler, aliens are
peddling yellow pants here,
do you need any?
There is no Fiddler, mate
What?
I've catapulted him
It's all right,
Vladimir Nickolaevich,
we have another catapult
That one was
broken anyway
I don't get it
I've pressed the
kappa and he flew away
Fiddler isn't needed, mate,
he was a waste of fuel
Turn back
We can't
We're out of luts,
we have to fly to
the luts station
Turn back or
I'll burn this fucking ketse!
Gedevan!
Fiddler!
Where could
he have gone?
I told you,
the etselops caught him
Let's go, mate
You've really
done it now!
Call the etselops
on the radio
We have no radio,
we threw it away
I'll check!
Etselop!
Put the tsak on, now!
He'll have to
do without
Put it on or he'll
trangluke you...
and the match
Hello
Listen, friend,
we lost our lad
around here,
did you see him?
What?
Sorry, I forgot
So did you
pick him up?
I told you Fiddler
wasn't needed!
How will we
buy luts now?
You are such
a silly bitch, mate
He's worse.
He's just a kyoo
I have
a proposition
We find Fiddler,
and then we'll go
to the local government
Get me some
sand, mate
We'll tell them
where we are from
they'll give us a
gravitsapa and we will
organise a mutually
beneficial trade...
you'll give us yellow pants
and we'll give you as many
matches as you want
We need a gravitsapa
to go to the government
The government lives on
another planet, mate
Uncle Vova!
I'm here!
Fiddler!
Where is my...
what's it called?
Tsak?
I have it
Give it to me
What for?
Just give it to me!
But there is
nobody here
This is mine
So keep it at the ready
Are you asleep?
No
Cheer up, Fiddler
If there is a gravitsapa
on Pluk, we'll find it
We've had it
much worse
Quiet
Stop!
Hey, would you give
us a lift to the Centre?
Patsak, stop
What?
That's close enough
What do you want?
Give us a lift!
3 chatls
We have no money,
but we'll work for it
What can you do?
Me? Anything!
Be specific
Vladimir Nickolaevich
works in construction
we'll build
you a house
And what
can you do?
Me?
He can play violin
Play!
I can't
Bye Patsaks
Wait, missy,
I can
Play!
Here?
Over there!
Wait, I'll sort
out the sound
Play
And sing
Right,
just a sec
How does it go...
Mother, mother,
what will we do?
Wow!
What?
I said wow
People like it
What?
People like it!
No
I could drum
How's that?
Foreman!
Fiddler isn't needed
It's OK, he
won't be a bother
Give us some
water, will you?
I said
- after the gig
We could just
take it, by force
You touch me and an
etselop will fly right here
and tear your legs off
Screw your etselop!
Calm down, Fiddler,
don't get the lady
all worked up
Hey, Foreman!
Look
Yeah, I got it
Look, do you have
a friend with a gravitsapa
and a pepelats?
Why?
If you could give
us a lift to Earth,
we'd give you both
a crate of ketse
I understand,
you don't believe in words.
What am I thinking?
That your wife is probably
calling the city morgue?
No, what am
I thinking now?
That you'll
give me ketse
See, it's true
What kind of moron
would think true stuff?
It's absurd
And because you say
what you don't think
and think what
you don't think
you sit in cages,
I can see this
whole bitter cataclysm
- and
Vladimir Nickolaevich, too
They say that Patsaks have
to sing in cages, do we
Stop freaking out
It's ok mate,
we'll sing next to it
Get in, he saw us,
he'll trangluke us!
We're not animals
What?
No, you'll get in!
Let go!
Stop it!
Get in, or he'll
melt us down!
Let's get in, Fiddler,
since the lady's asking
Get in
One, two, three...
Dance!
Dance
You know what?
Go book another band
What?
Be right back
We have to run
Boys, give it a push,
it's uphill
Now this we can do
Accelerate!
Bye, dorks!
I'll tell everybody
what this clown PG
did to the planet!
Patsaks are trampling
all over Chatlans!
Everything in place?
She stole
my aftershave
Women
Let me.
What do you have
in there - lead?
I got it,
uncle Vova
I have no idea
where to look
Where is Earth?
Me and comrade Moshkov,
being Patsaks,
could charge 2 chatls
per gig max
Water, luts and bribes
to etselops - at least a chatl a day
And a gravitsapa is
worth half a ketse!
That's 2200 chatls
Divide by 365,
minus weekends,
equals 6
I simply couldn't get
back in less than 6 years
Gedevan Alexandrovich,
I only have your word for it
Do you have any
proof that you came
back from outer space
and not sold the
violin and spent all
that time in the disco?
This is a
local mineral
This is a chatl
This is a tsak
A metal nut and
a sample of sand
are appended to
the report I gave
to the Dean's secretary
so she could
forward it to
the United Nations
Where?
To the United Nations
Look, Gedevan Alexandrovich,
you're an adult
You've studied here
for a half-term and then
disappeared for years
And now you come
back with a stone,
a piece of
Georgian ceramics
and a bell,
and you expect
me to believe...
And by the way,
if you are so musical,
why weren't you in
our student orchestra?
Excuse me, Fiddler,
but this is just koo!
END OF PART ONE