Brief
CHATLAN - PATSAK
DICTIONARY
Ketze - Match
Tsak - Nose Bell
Etsih - Box for Prisoners
Etselop - Policeman
Pepelats - Spaceship
Gravitsapa - Pepelats Engine Part
Kyoo - A mild swear-word
Koo - All other words
Hi!
Hello
Long time no see
Bye!
Just a second!
I have a proposition
What?
What do we
think about you?
Come on, penetrate
my brain
Why are you bothering us?
What do you want?
Have you no shame?
Have you?
We are poor hungry artists!
What have we ever done to you?
Why are you stalking us?
Give me the widget
Come on
One, two, three...
Mother, mother,
what will we do? Koo!
Shut up,
you're tone deaf
Uncle Vova,
let's go again!
They love it!
They understand it!
One, two...
Etselop!
Artists, where's
our deathtrap?
Pepelats?
Yes
Over there
We're out of luts
All because
of you, bitch!
Fiddler! What are you doing?
Vandal!
Leave me alone!
Mate, this is a last breath,
a grave, a cemetery
Mate
And you say you were 'second league'
He was just bragging
It's not fair, you win
because of my brains
If you had brains, you'd be
studying Foreign Politics instead
of messing with our mood here
Let's play again.
You bet the violin,
the case and the tooth-stick
And this
Ok?
Ok. You bet the widget,
visator and Mr Uef's life source
Sure
Let's play
Uncle Vova, you have
to twist the tsapa
Here, you do it!
I can't,
I'm Chatlan
Oh sure, when it
comes to advising,
everyone is a Chatlan!
Checkmate
Not fair!
You thought up
bad moves for me!
You have to play
using your brains
How could he?
He's never seen these dolls before
Not my problem.
Give me my winnings
No way
Uef, have you ever seen
such a little Patsak acting like
such a materialistic kyoo?
Never. I keep saying,
Fiddler is not needed
Hey, boss!
And you say - tsapa!
So nobody
sings in cages?
Mr Bee, on Earth
we only cage animals
Are animals Chatlans?
I don't know. Similar
Is a nightingale a Patsak?
Why Patsak?
You said it doesn't
sing in a cage
Patsak then
See, you are as
racist as we on Pluk
Only, the power belongs not
to Chatlans, but to Patsaks
Like you and your
nightingale friend
Let me
Here, 4 gulps
Give the water to the children
You owe us 6042 boxes.
Fiddler, write it down
I have
Do you want any?
No
It's free
What are you doing?
What about me?
I'll pay 10 more boxes,
have some water
Kin-dza-dza!
A boat!
It's not a boat,
it's a luts station
Let's fill up!
Can't
It's a machine, next one
has a woman. We'll sing -
she'll cut us a deal, got it?
Stop slacking, uncle Vova
Let's go mate
If this was a sea,
why aren't there any shells?
Do you still have
seas on Earth?
We have seas, rivers
and decent people, Mr Uef
You are such
barbarians, I could cry
It's a shame my boss
can't see me, I'd get a raise
Hush Uncle Vova,
a lady is watching us
They took away the woman,
and put in a machine
Buy as much as you can, we'll
fly at least part of the way
We can't. Luts are
10 chatls per charge,
we have only 7
How far is the Centre?
160 kilometers
Uncle Vova!
Uef has more chatls
In his right boot
Hey, Chatlan!
What?
Take off your right boot
What for?
Come on, koo, koo
Kyoo, bitch!
Squat!
Why? They are not etselops
It's PG and his Patsak
You can get etsih with nails
for life by not squatting!
But who is he?
Did you see that?
Yeah. It's a hologram, mate!
The Violin!
Calm down! Freeze!
And you said - koo!
It's not a blimp moron,
it's the last breath of Mr PG
Rubbish
How could one man breathe
so much air while dying?
It's absurd
What are you saying!
PG is alive!
And I'm happy!
I'm even happier
Climb inside
Plastic?
No
Is there a normal way
into this supermarket?
To get in normally, we have
to pay in chatls mate
Let's go
Get lost!
Fiddler, Patsaks go there
What are they doing?
It's Mr PG's fourth pump
I love PG very much!
I koo him even more!
Here they make
water out of luts
What are they saying?
They are selling
What are they selling?
Everything
Let's buy a gravitsapa!
It's in another department
We first need to find out
Earth's tentura number
Yellow pants - koo twice!
Think of the orbit diameter
of your planet
I don't remember
Fiddler, you do it
Fiddler isn't needed,
you do it!
Oh, all right
Think of your planets
core density
Density?
I can't remember
I see
Think of the planets in your Galaxy,
as many as you know
Jupiter, Mars, Venus...
Where is my divination crystal?
It was right there!
Fiddler, put it back!
I thought it was just a
piece of glass, rubbish
Stupid cow
Enough
Stop rattling your brains moron
Here is your planet
Here is your planet: 013 in tentura,
just left of Ursa Major
If you want to talk,
that's extra
Pardon?
Think of your phone number
And tell them about the matches
Hello, I'm listening
Speak there
Hello, I'm listening!
Speak, time is money
Hello, Lucy
Vovka?
Can you hear me ok? It's me!
Vovka, where are you?
I'm here. How are you?
How's our son?
Where are you, Vovka?
I'm here, in this place,
I'll explain later
How's mum?
Have you seen her?
Yes I have. I'm asking you,
where are you?
Hey, she-Patsak, quit messing with us,
go buy two crates of ketse!
Or we'll find him another...
Lucy!
My dear!
Call Manokhin, tell him
that the keys to the
building store are in my office,
under the cabinet,
do you understand?
Oh, I understand
Please dial Batumi 3-47-57
and ask for Alik
No.
Get lost thief
Is something wrong?
Everything's fine,
but Earth is very far away
It will take 7 minutes instead of 5
Let's go and prepare some
tsapa for the gravitsapa
Astronauts!
Which one is tsapa?
It's a rusty metal nut mate
Everything is rusty here
That one is the rustiest
What are you doing,
are you nuts?
Wow, Lucy and Manokhin
have been transported!
Uncle Vova!
The match was in the hat!
Weird. Why would they leave?
Weird? They have a match
to buy a gravitsapa, and
they know where Earth is!
Comrade etselop!
They stole from us!
Please catch them!
40 chatls
Our money is with the guide.
That's not even my violin!
They did not koo in
front of a video of PG.
What are you staring at?
I'll tell that you knew and did nothing,
you'll be fucking trangluked! Right?
I didn't do nothing.
I pressed the kappa at once
Fiddler is a witness
Calling all patrols!
There's nothing there
Open it
Let them see
It's vinegar
That's none of your business
The Patsak will be trangluked,
the Chatlan gets etsih
for life - with nails
Brother Patsak tell them
the truth, that I squatted,
it was this Chatlan...
Shut up parasite!
You shut up!
Vovka, my friend!
Gedevan Alexandrovich!
Tell them it was him!
He was the one
who did not squat
And I will give
you the Pepelats
Uncle Vova,
the Pepelats is mine!
Calm down
Everything's fine.
Everybody squatted like monkeys.
I was wrong
And it was me who
brought the ketse here
What ketse?
That match you
took out of the hat
There was no match
Uncle Vova, mate,
what are you saying!
Sorry, I forgot
There was no match
You two, etsih without nails - for life.
Until the fee of 500 chatls is paid
Thank you!
Patsak, fix the violin and sing
Fiddler, work that widget!
Guys, we were just kidding,
we thought it would be a laugh!
See you!
Hello, Earthling!
I knew one day your explorations
would carry you to this planet
Greetings from
Vladimir Nickolaevich Moshkov,
construction foreman from Moskow
and Gedevan Alexidze
from Batumi
We were the first to set foot
onto this wretched sand in the
backwater of the Universe
Brother Patsak
add some fuel
Give me something else then
Maybe by this time,
some people who knew
me are still alive
Please tell them that
I did not steal the violin...
Look, good as new
Here is another piece
Yeah, this sort of
thing can happen
Is it nutritious?
Earthlings!
You really shouldn't have
pressed it like that
I only found you
thanks to the dial memory
I'm returning your sock,
thank you
If you wish,
I can transport
you back to Earth,
I found out your tentura number
But you have to hurry,
one second here
is half a year there
I have a proposition
We go to Earth,
get some matches,
go back, sell them...
get our guys
out of the jail,...
go to Moscow
and you go home
I can't do that,
I only have 3 charges
That's great!
Enough to go there,
here and back again
And what about me?
Listen, freind
Make up your mind
I'm counting to three.
One...
Wait
Two...
Please understand,
they are in jail
because of me
And my little son has
a beard like this by now!
Two and a half...
Two and a half!
I cannot do this
Three
Who needs all this stuff?
Stupid tsaks,
all this rubbish...
We'll never...
Where did you
get this from? Huh?
It was just lying around
in the planetarium,
on the shelf
Fiddler...
My dear little klepto
You've pinched
a gravitsapa!
Patsaks!
Why are you
singing standing up?
It's only allowed over there
The Etselop didn't
let us sing there
Here you can only
sing on your knees
We're fine as we are
Come on,
give us money
Now, now, be good
Strangers in the Koo.
Uncle Vova,
here is your coat...
it's walking, wearing my hat
Hi!
How's life?
What's new on Pluk?
Sing
I'm having a bad voice day
Sing!
Vladimir Nicolaevich
I can't stand
this any longer
Calm down, Fiddler
How much is this?
I think we've
made enough
How much is this one?
Estelop!
Patsaks!
Why aren't you
wearing muzzles?
Turn around
New order
from Mr PG -
all Patsaks must
now wear muzzles
and be happy
This is for me,
this is for you
and this is for you
Why aren't you happy?
Answer me!
Come on, Chatlan,
get your tranglucator
Put it on
Yes, sir!
And be happy
I'm so happy!
Look, PG is here!
Where?
Get up!
Open your mouth!
Open wider!
Fiddler
Get me a gag
Quick!
Turn around!
Nose
Give back our money
Here, hold this
Take this off
If you think it's
not a tranglucator
it will be the last thought
in your Chatlan head
Show us the shortest
way to the etsih
Go!
Everybody down!
Stay there for half an hour
Move!
Faster!
Excuse us, granny
That was PG's mother
Is it a video of PG?
No. It's the man himself
Everybody
get in the tub, now!
Open the door
Stay there for 24 hours
Koo, or not koo?
Here it is
Which number?
The last one
Hello
Hey, Chatlan
Sing
Fiddler, stop it
Last but one then
Get lost!
Hello,
Gedevan Alexandrovich
Hello
Get out of there
We can't
They'll catch us again
Stop
We have a gravitsapa
Koo, Uncle Vova!
Cut it
Right here
All together now!
Uncle Vova, help me
with the etsih
Leave it!
Vladimir Nicolaevich!
Humankind worked for
millenia just to get one
stone from the Moon
And here we have
a live alien and an etsih
made of an unknown metal!
I said, leave it!
Tsapa
Yes sir, tsapa
Tsapa!
Press the tsapa!
I did!
Are we flying?
Starting her up...
Come on, gentlemen,
before they come
to their senses!
You're not helping!
And we've landed
Landed where?
Hanut
What's Hanut?
The planet where
I was born
And me
It's night
Now it's always night here
Put this on
Why?
There's no bloody air here
So how do you live here?
Nobody has lived here for ages
Plukans trangluked the planet...
while we were on tour
Why?
Because we did
not get them first
Why did you want
to get them?
So they'd stop bugging
us with their existense
Did everybody die?
Of course
Vovka, I have a proposition
This planet now costs peanuts
63 chatls
We'll tour the galaxy for a
month singing 'Mother, Mother'...
and the planet is ours!
Another month and we'll
even be able to buy air
93 chatls
Everyone who has no air
will rush straight here
The air belongs to us
They will crawl before us,
and we will spit on them
What for?
For fun
What kind of fun is that?
He's so young
Half of the planet could be
yours, the other half ours. OK?
This is very tempting
But we need to
go back to Earth
Let's move, the supermarket
shuts in half an hour
Vovka, relax
Look
We're here
Earth is there
And there is Alpha
On Alpha they turn
us into cactuses
Earth is in
anti-tentura, dear
We cannot get
there, understand?
Why?
That's how it is.
It's just my luck really
A Pepelats can't
get to Earth!
So quit arguing
Ok?
Let's go and decide how
we will share the planet
Did you learn about
this in the planetarium?
Yes mate
That's why you
stole the match?
Of course
Uncle Vova,
they're lying!
Don't believe them
Get us to Earth, now!
No, Gedevan
They're not lying
They'd crawl across the Universe
on their stomachs for a
chance to get some matches
Vovka, it's a
silly thing to do
This air has
only 2% oxygen
Gedevan
Don't do this,
you're so young.
Live!
Maybe things will change
Fiddler isn't needed, Uncle Vova
Patsak!
You're going to
die in a moment
so tell us the
truth for once
Why didn't you teleport
home with that jerk
while you could?
What did you want?
Purple pants?
PG's bathtub?
Tell us,
what did you want?
Gedevan,
dear friend
You tell me
You can tell me,
I'm one of us
My mother was Georgian
He says his mother
was a local Georgian
Uef!
I don't care
I will koo them to Alpha!
And you,
lousy Chatlan
put on the tsak
and squat when you
talk to a Patsak!
Hanut is a Patsak
planet mate
Say it again
You will
catapult us to Alpha
and try to stop
the ship in its orbit
There's no way we
can break over there!
Don't interrupt
Carry on mate
On Alpha, while they
transport us to Earth
we will hold on to the bottom of
the space-transportation gadget
and the gadget will
transport with us
On Earth,...
we will buy you
4 crates of matches
Carry on mate
How many times do
we have to go over it?
Let's go
Because of you I will spend
an eternity in a plant pot
and you can't
even do this for us
My dear, good friends
Lets' fly already or
at least close this door
I can't stand the sight
of you any longer
I'm going to be sick
any moment now
So long mate
And we're flying
Break!
How can I?
You've drunk all our
breaking fluid! Alcoholic
Can't be good for him
Turn off your antlers
They can't be turned off
Take them off then
They might break
I think we've landed
That's how it
was the last time
All right
Put on your
gas mask
What about tsak?
No, they'll have
to do without
Earth!
''Om the river, om the far river bamk... ''
No
This isn't Earth
Hello
We're Patsaks
from planet Earth
Who are you?
This is planet Alpha
Tell Decont here,
your coordinates
and she will transport
you to the starting point
Have a nice day
Please give me
your planet number
013 in tentura
It's somewhere here
To the left of Ursa Major
This is not necessary
Would you please
hold your hands
Miss, what did
you do with them?
They are in the
Second Greenhouse
Would you please
hold your hands
Do you really turn
people into cactuses?
Only people from Pluk
They're not Plukans,
they're Hanutians
This is not relevant
Would you please
put the mask on
Why?
You have beautiful air
That's why
Would you get a load of her!
Calm down.
Put it on
Gedevan!
On behalf of the
people of Earth, please...
Let them go
Who can make
this decision?
Abradox can
But...
Take us to him
Take us to him!
Or I'll take off the
mask and breathe
on everything!
You shouldn't worry
Our greenhouses provide
the best environment
Blossoming, microclimate,
peace and quiet
You should envy them
Then my dear, why do
you frolic around...
instead of sitting
in a plant pot?
Please watch your step
you have already
broken 3 blades of grass
Friend!
We want to ask
you something
No need to continue
No
Our proximity to the
Kin-dza-dza Galaxy...
is our greatest problem
They are plagued by
yearnings and desires
vile desires!
Being transformed
into plants
is much better for them...
and for everyone else!
Maybe we should bring
them here and ask them
Let them decide what's better
If we give that sort
the opportunity to decide
about anything...
Girly, are you the
smartest people around?
Did somebody tell you
or did you decided
it all on your own?
Let's not waste time
You are creatures
from anti-tentura
That means I have an
obligation to transport you...
to the starting
point of your journey
Or, we can send
you back in time...
to the moment when you can
choose your fate for yourselves
Make a decision
I don't understand
Back in time?
I can send you
to the past
Back to Pluk
Can you send
one of us to Earth
and the other
one back in time?
Vladimir Nickolaevich
No way will I let you
return to Pluk alone
Listen you
send us back in time!
How long was I fixing the
violin? About 50 minutes?
About 50
Brother Patsak
a guy with a sock
will be here soon
Tell him to meet
us at the etsih
Do you know the etsih?
Sure
Will you show us?
Give me something else then
Everybody, rest
for half an hour!
Thank you friends
Carry on playing, boys
Fiddler, hurry up!
Not again! You bitches!
Yep.
Now get out of there
Like hell!
It's better here
than on Alpha
Get them out
We'll have a space-transport
gizmo in a minute
Vladimir Nickolaevich!
You owe us 11,000 boxes
Fiddler has it
written down
11,020
I have a proposition
Vovka
We will transport together
right into the
supermarket
and after we
buy everything...
There is no 'after'
We're only going to Earth
Forever?
Forever
Me, on a planet where
they don't know who has to
squat in front of whom?
Nonsense
Give us the gravitsapa
and you do what you want
Uncle Uef, uncle Bee,
You will be very welcome there!
No, my friend
A society without the colour
differentiation of pants...
is a society without purpose
And without a purpose...
Enough with the philosophy,
he's going to appear soon
Make up your mind
Are you going with us?
Just give us
the gravitsapa!
Give it to them
Pity
So
We should say our farewells
I kind of got used to you
Me too
Well
Take care
Friends!
Patsaks!
Here is your sock
back, thank you
If you wish...
Friend!
What system is your gadget?
Might I take a look?
Regular system
You press a button
- and you're home
Hi
How was your day?
Some pipes burst at
Manokhin's building site
''Mother, mother, what will we do,
Mother, mother, how will we live?''
How's our A-student?
He's out with friends
Vovka! I forgot to buy
bread, will you go?
And buy some noodles!
Comrade
How could I get to
the Old Arbat street?
Turn right over there
Thank you
Fiddler?
Uncle Vova?
Fiddler!
Uncle Vova!
The End